《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on prison break
那群混蛋死了还好 我们却辛苦的活着
Those ass-hats are worth more dead than you and I are alive.
有人会得到那笔钱 最好是我
Somebody's gonna get that money-- might as well be me.
你知道 像那种工作
You know,a job like that
有个帮手会更轻松点
might go a little smoother with an extra pair of hands.
派些潜水员到河里去
I want divers down in the river.
你是斯科特 科波莱内吗?
Are you Scott Kolbrenner?
那你就是黛布拉 珍了
You must be Debra Jean.
很高兴认识你
It's nice to meet you.
我也是
Yeah,same here.
很显然菲波纳奇会再次出庭
Apparently,Fibonacci's coming up for air again,
如果他在那个听证会上作证
and if he testifies at that hearing,
很多人都会被拖下水
a lot of people are going down.
卡罗琳 他们把她带走了
Caroline. They're taking her in.
当然 我会密切关注她的
Of course,I'll keep an eye on her.
你好 我叫莎拉 是个瘾君子
Hi,my name is Sara,and I'm an addict.
我叫兰斯 也是个瘾君子
Hi,my name's Lance,and I'm an addict.
你好 兰斯
Hi,Lance.
你干得真他妈的好
You did one hell of a job,Doc.
你可以离开了
It's okay for you to leave now.
我可以走 你却不行
Oh,I'm leaving; you're not.
去哪里 先生
Where to,sir?
犹他州
Utah.
准备好了? 是
Ready? Yeah.
是他们中的哪个?
So which one of them was it?
可能是斯科菲尔德
Maybe Scofield.
很可能还能找到他的哥哥
Probably gonna find his brother in there,too.
你还会见她吗 那个医生
Are you meeting up with her,the doctor?
我也不清楚
I don't know.
我就知道这小婊子会带我们找到他们
I knew the little whore would take us right to 'em.
到了墨西哥 你们打算干什么?
What happens when you get to Mexico?
你们打算去哪?
Where will you go?
你不知道为好
It's best if you don't know.
所有人都不知道最好
It's best for everyone.
下个镇子你就下车
We'll drop you off in the next town,
我说过会给你寄一万美金的
and I'll wire you that 10,000,like I said.
不会超过两个星期
Shouldn't take more than a week or two.
迈克尔 我们有麻烦了
Michael.What's hell going on?
抓紧 抓紧了
Hold on! Hold on! Hold on!
是谁?
Who is it?
是贝利克
It's Bellick!
抓紧
Hold on.
抓紧 抓紧了...
Hold on,hold on,hold on.
抓紧
Hold on.
这东西就不能开快一点吗
Can this thing go any faster?!
你认为呢?
What do you think?!
小心 小心!
Look out!
都不准动
Nobody move!
真高兴又见到你了 孩子
Oh,good to see you again,boy.
大家都不想受伤 老大
No need for anyoneto get hurt,Boss.
老大?  这里再也用不着讲礼貌了
Boss? Oh,there's no need for formalities anymore there,Sink.
我再也不是公务员了
I'm no longer an employee of the state,
都是拜你所赐
thanks to you.
我想是有人想要那笔赏金
I think somebody wants that reward.
这跟赏金无关 伙计
Oh,it's not about reward money,friend.
你的朋友曼彻全都告诉我了
Your pal Manche told me
关于韦斯特莫兰德隐藏的
all about your little treasure hunt
小小的寻宝游戏
for Westmoreland's stash.
上车
Get in the car.
我们要去犹他州了
We're going to Utah.
这里所有的警察都在找你们
All the cops following you all over the country,
但是都是追着你们的尾巴跑
when all they had to do was tail the tail,you know?
走快点 我的摇钱树
Let's move it,convict.
既然你们已经知道犹他的那笔钱 为什么还需要我们
If you know about the money in Utah,why do you need us?
越狱太过紧张
Well,the excitement of the escape,
在那老家伙挂之前
Manche didn't hear everything Westmoreland said
曼彻没把韦斯特莫兰德的话都听完
before the old bird kicked the bucket,
但是他听清楚了 犹他和五百万
but he heard enough: Utah and five million.
加上你们就够了
You'll fill in the blanks.
别在这里装腔作势 傻瓜
Don't even think about getting cute,smart-ass.
现在你和你哥哥带我们
Now,you and your brother are gonna take me
去找那笔钱
right to where that money is,
否则这婊子就死得很快
or the whore gets dead real fast.
不信就试试看
Ask me if I'm bluffing.
从斯科菲尔德公寓底下那条河里
The dredging of the river beneath Scofield's apartment
找到一些东西
bore some fruit.
河床底找到一个硬盘
Found a hard drive under the river bed.
上面的序列号
Serial numbers match an order
跟他进监狱前几个月
that Scofield put in with Dell
购买的戴尔电脑相吻合
a few months before he was incarcerated.
现在他们恢复了上面12%的数据
They've recovered about 12 percent of the data so far.
这个对我们有什么帮助
And this is helping us how?
血液检验已经出来了
Blood tests came back.
爆炸地点都是B型
B-negative all over that crash site.
斯科菲尔德和布伦斯也都是...
Scofield and Burrows are both...
B型 -我知道
B-negative. -I know.
我去联系媒体
I'll reach out to the media.
别忙这么做
How about don't.
如果我们对外宣称策划越狱的
If it gets out that the guy who...
主犯可能已经死了
...who masterminded this whole thing is possibly dead,
其他六个家伙就会更加警觉
the other six cons are gonna get their guards up even more.
我们的策略是 抱歉...
It is our policy-- excuse me...
我们的策略是
It is our policy
在确认他们死亡之前先别声张
not to announce deaths until they're confirmed!
我们已经看到汽车爆炸和血液检测
We've got an exploding car and a blood match.
那就做更多检验
Well,then do more tests.
对什么做检验?
On what?
对汽车保险杆 我不知道 也不在乎
On the bumper. I don't know. I don't care.
先别忙 我想让外面的那些家伙
Just delay. I want those guys out there
更得意 而不是更小心
getting more complacent,not more careful.
继续向他们的核计划迈进
...to forge ahead with its nuclear program.
国内新闻 从福克斯河监狱
In national news,the eight escaped convicts
越狱的8名逃犯
from Fox River Penitentiary in Illinois
目前仍在逃中...
are still at large,and...
我正在听呢
Hey,I was listening to that.
是啊
Yeah.
但是我想听这个
Yeah,I want to hear this.
真的吗
Really?
你喜欢约翰·丹佛?
You like John Denver?
当然
Yeah.
带我回家
Take me home
到你的家
To your place
我有现钞...
I've got cash
西弗吉尼亚
In West Virginia
带我回家 我的乡村妓女
Take me home,my country ho...
不错 很不错
This is good,this is good.
歌唱的不错 都可以弃学专业当歌手了
Don't quit your day job.
什么
What?
通常我是喝点龙舌兰酒才开始K歌
Nah,I just need a little tequila to get my karaoke on.
不错
Yeah.
慢着 减速
Here,yo,slow down.
我们现在只有65码 限速60...
We're doing,like,65 in a 60...
减速
Yo,slow down.
好吧 老兄
All right,Dad.
我们不能被查到 伙计
Yo,we can't be having that,man.
开张罚单就是200美刀
Tickets are,like,200 bones.
是啊
Yeah.
我从没想过要说这句话 斯科菲尔德
I never thought I'd say this,Scofield,
我真的感谢上帝让你来到福克斯河
but I thank God for the day you walked into Fox River.
然后又逃了出去
And out of it.
没事的
It's gonna be okay.
我可不想听你说这句话
I don't want to hear from you right now.
你告诉我什么都不会发生
You told me nothing would happen.
你向我保证了
You promised me.
她生气了
That's one pissed off commie
你可得自己解决 斯科菲尔德
you got on your hands there,Scofield.
你妈妈没告诉你怎么对待一个女人吗?
Didn't your mama tell you how to treat a lady?
还是她自己就是这样的一个婊子 林肯
Or was she a whore like this one? Linc!
有问题吗 布伦斯
Got a problem there,Burrows?
我们只需要你们中的一个
We only need one of you
带我们去找那笔钱
to take us to the money.
记好了
Remember that.
我们走 伙计
Let's go,buddy.
走吧
Let's go.
在说结婚祝词的时候 我完全喝醉了
I'd been really drunk at the wedding speech.
这是我第一次
And this was the first time
在这里跟大家说
that we'd spoken since then.
让我得到净化
And it was cleansing.
真的让我得到净化
It was really cleansing.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你的参与 拉尔夫
Good share,Ralph.
我们没多少时间了
Well,we're out of time.
除非还有特别想说的
Unless there are any burning desires...
我想谈一下
Actually,I'd like to...
如果有时间允许的话
you know,if there's time.
当然
Of course.
我叫兰斯 我是个瘾君子
I'm Lance,and I'm an addict.
你好 兰斯
Hi,Lance.
上周我妈妈死于多发性硬化症
My,uh,mother died of M.S. last week.
她是...
She just...
一点点耗光的
gave out.
就像我的外祖父 我的姐姐一样
Just like my grandfather did,just like my sister did.
如果任其发展下去  我也一样
Just like I...
可以打断一下吗
Um,if-if I may?
兰斯  多发性硬化症通常不遗传
Lance,M.S. isn't usually considered genetic.
是吗 什么 你是医生吗?
Really? What-What are you,a doctor?
我是 事实上
Uh,I-I am,actually.
抱歉
Sorry.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
好了 大家都面对墙
All right,everybody,face the wall
看着前方
and look straight ahead!
眼睛看前面
Eyes front.
旅途怎么样啊？
How was your flight?
一路颠簸
Bumpy.
一切都准备好了吧?
Everything is ready?
我们有艘货船泊在军港里
We got a container ship down at the navy yard.
船长是我们的人
The captain's one of ours.
船上有个贵宾间
He's got a stateroom
旅客清单上标记此房间装货用
listed as a cargo hold on the manifest.
你和你家人上这条船
You and your family will be on it
明天就起航
when it sets sail tomorrow.
六天后 约翰 你就会在撒丁岛了
Six days from now,John,you'll be in Sardinia.
干的好
Good work.
西尔维娅
Sylvia.
爸爸!
Dad!
我们想你
We missed you.
结束了
It's over.
我也想你们
I missed you,too.
好了 都结束了
It's over,it's over.
来吧
Come on.
你在搞什么鬼
What the hell are you doing?
管好你自己的事吧
Mind your own business.
你这没用的东西
What kind of son of a bitch
居然在车里不放备用胎?
doesn't have a spare tire in his car?
你不是还用得着我
The kind that already used it.
你真是个没用的家伙
Well,then you're just the sad sack
得回城里去弄个新的了
that has to go back into town to get a new one.
有将近三里啊
That's like three miles.
是的
That's right.
好了 大家都出来
All right,everybody out.
那边 走吧
That way,come on.
小心点
Careful.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
放轻松点
Just relax.
我信你说的每句话
You know,I believed everything you told me,
我做了你让我做的每件事
and I did everything you asked.
我为了你不惜冒生命危险
I risked my life for you.
为了什么?就为了那1万美元吗？ 我在冒生命的危险啊！
For what? For $10,000,I risked my life?
而与此同时
And this entire time,
有500万美元在那里等你
you've had $5 million just waiting there.
你是个混蛋 迈克尔
You're a bastard,Michael.
不好受吧 我倒希望这样的事
For all the aggravation,I hope you got to hit that
你多碰到几次 斯科菲尔德
a few times,Scofield.
呵呵呵
Ba-ba-boom-bah.
我们去棚房那里等吧
We're going to wait it out in that shack.
进去 动作麻利点
Go in there.Come on.
小宝贝 别停下
Fantasia,get going.
我想和你谈谈... 单独
I need to talk to you... alone.
你要怎样？
What do you want?
毁了他的生活就像他曾经毁了我的那样
To ruin his life like he's ruined mine.
你看见了什么，先生？
And what did you see, sir?
我车子过热了
I was overheating,
所以我停车了
so I pulled in.
这车已经在这了
This car was already here.
你呢？
What about you?
我在看书
Oh, I was reading;
我什么也没看见
I didn't see nothing.
嘿，伙计
Hey, buddy.
你从哪来的?
Where you coming from?
我?
Me?
我刚刚撞了下头 长官
I was just hitting the head,boss.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
克莱德
Clyde.
克莱德 梅
Clyde May.
有身份证件吗 梅先生?
You got any ID,Mr. May?
我不能...
I don't,uh...
我不能再开车了 所以证件不随身带
drive anymore,so don't really have ID per se.
在坎大哈的时候 有帮阿拉伯兔崽子
Camel jockey left a big box of boom-boom
在我吉普车下面埋了雷...
under my jeep back in Kandahar.
你是军人?
You military?
过去是
Was.
哪辆车是你的?
Which one's your vehicle?
就这两条腿
These two sleds right here.
也就是，总之就靠这移动了
That is,in between rides,anyhow.
怎么没带行李啊？
Ain't much of a bag to be hitchhiking with.
我喜欢轻装上路啊
I travel light.
你就这样凭空走到这里的？
And you're just hoofing it out here in the middle of nowhere?
我总有权利四处看看这个国家
I do have the right to see a little bit of the country
这个我为之断手的国家吧?
I lost my hand for,don't I?
告诉我究竟怎么了 长官？
Why don't you tell me what this is all about,Officer.
我们找到了辆车 但是没有司机
We got a vehicle here without a driver,
现在呢
and at present,
你是这里唯一一个没车的司机
you're the only driver without a vehicle.
嘿 就是为了这件事啊?
Hell,is that what this is all about?
为什么不早说啊?
Why didn't you say so?
有个脏兮兮的嬉皮士刚才跑进去拉屎
Dirty hippie kid dropping a deuce in the facilities.
就是开着这辆车来的
Came in with that car
不到两分钟前
not two minutes ago.
去查查
Check it out.
你以前是陆军部队的？
What were you,Army?
当然不是
Hell no.
海军陆战队
Corps.
哦 是这样啊
Well,then.
永远效忠（注:海军陆战队的宣言）
Semper fi,brother.
哪个番号的？
What outfit were you?
第196师
196th.
第196师?
196th?
从没听说过啊
Never heard of it.
在哪的?
Where they out of?
嘿!
Hey,Elkind!
这他妈怎么回事?
What the hell,man?
我什么都没做
I didn't do nothing.
在他背包里发现了这些
Found these in his knapsack,
在他告诉我他没车后
after he said he had no car.
什么?
What?
永远效忠
Semper fi,brother.
Semper fi.
不用使劲了 没什么用的
Stop stressing; it doesn't do any good.
或许你应该开始使劲
Maybe you ought to  start stressing,
如果他们准备一枪毙了你
if they're going to put a bullet in our heads.
他们需要我们
They need us.
他们需要我们帮他们拿到钱
They need us to get that money.
我真佩服你的乐观精神
I admire your optimism.
她的立场不定
She's rolling,man.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
你想要毁了斯科菲尔德的一生
So you want to ruin  Scofield's life.
欢迎加入
Well,get in line.
你到底想要什么?
What are you really looking for?
和你一样 钱！
Same as you... money.
钱? 你想要钱?
Money? You want money?
一万美元 怎么样?
Ten grand,how's that sound?
我们现在就干 在那地板上
We do it right now,right there on those floorboards.
想都别想
Not in a thousand years.
那就给我滚
Beat it then.
你身上没有其他我要的东西
You got nothing else I need.
男的都这样啊
Typical man.
我说的是数百万的美元
I'm talking about millions of dollars,
你他妈就为了做爱连钱都不要了
and you'd piss it away for sex.
是的
That's right.
我之前还希望你不要让斯科菲尔德赢了你
And I was hoping you wouldn't let Michael outsmart you,too.
斯科菲尔德 没赢任何人
Scofield ain't outsmarting no one.
你以为那胎是偶然爆掉的啊?
You think that tire went flat by accident?
你有什么要告诉我?
What are you offering?
我能找到钱在哪
I can find out where the money is.
他信我
He trusts me.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
我应得的那份
My fair share.
你找到钱在哪 你就可以得到
You find out where that money is,your fair share
20万美元
is $200,000.
5百万只分这点? 这不公平...
Out of five million? It's not even...
我拿着枪呢 小妞
I got the gun,girl.
我让你加入 你该感到庆幸了
You're lucky you're a partner at all.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back
菲波纳奇在华盛顿
Fibonacci's in D.C.
是的 他还在丹佛 亚特兰大 迈阿密...
Yeah,and he's in Denver,Atlanta,Miami...
不不不不
No,no,no,no,no.
这次是真的
This time,it's for real.
他又要作证了
He's testifying again.
他现在在华盛顿
He's in Washington right now.
环球旅馆116房间
The Globe Hotel,Room 116.
这个消息可靠吗?
Is this information any good?
是从新泽西来的
It's from New Jersey.
费希赫德 汤米想示好
Fishhead Tommy wants to pay tribute.
去准备车
Get the car.
好的
Okay.
看看这里 约翰
Look at this room,John.
看看
Look.
我们又可以成为一家人了
We can be a family again.
但是你又要去拿这一切冒险了
But you want to risk it all,
你不重视我们 为了什么 为了报仇吗?
disrespect us,and for what,for vengeance?
他背叛了我
He betrayed me.
我不管
I don't care.
他背叛了我们
He betrayed us.
对不起 你... 你永远不会明白
I'm sorry you... will never understand
在监狱的时候... 到底发生了什么？
what happens... when you're in prison.
你又会被关进去的...
But you could go back to pris...
我向天发誓...
I swear to God...
我宁愿死也不会回去
I'd rather die than go back.
没有回头路了 没了 再也没了
There's no going back,never,ever again.
约翰 耶稣拯救了你 不要违背他的意愿
Christ saved you,John.Don't turn your back on him.
不要不顾我们
Don't turn your back on us.
我...
I...
我不知道 大约离冈尼森河20里
I don't know,about 20 miles from Gunnison.
他来了  我得挂了
He's coming; I have to go.
是谁啊?
Who was that?
不是别人 是我爸爸
Nobody,it's just my father.
哦 嘿 听着
Oh. Hey,listen.
我们在下个汽车旅店打尖行吗?
Do you mind if we stop at the next motel?
还只有大约四点啊?
It's only like 4:00?
是的 但是我们已经开了很久
Yeah,but we've been driving forever.
好吧 我来开
It's cool,I'll drive.
我真的想停一停
I really just want to stop.
但是如果我们现在上路的话 或许...
But if we get on the road now,maybe...
斯科特 这是我的车
Scott,it's my car,
我很累了 好吗?
and I'm tired of being in it,okay?
好吧
All right.
-听过那个暴料的来电吗? -你能相信吗?
Can you believe it?
全靠这个小人物菲波纳奇
Of all the players in this thing,
给了我们提示 快点
it's the rat that could give us our first collar. Come on.
你们俩想上厕所 都给我摒住
You guys need to use the can,hold it.
小宝贝 如果你想小便
If you need to tinkle,sweet pea,
我随时可以照看你
I'll watch you any time.
坐下
Sit down.
把手放后面
Hands behind your back.
慢慢来
Took your time.
要获得一个男人的信任得花点时间
It takes time to gain a man's confidence.
你说的没错
You're right.
他会怀疑我说的任何事的
He'll bite on anything I say.
你告诉我我们在哪设计抓他
You just tell me where we trap him,
然后我就告诉他钱在哪
and I'll tell him that's where the money is.
嘿 你就是刚才加油站的那个人 是吗?
Hey,you're the guy from the gas station,right?
是的
Yeah.
刚才我的车出了点问题
I'm the guy who was having car trouble.
现在听起来有点咕噜咕噜响?
Seems to be purring along now,huh?
是的 是抽水机的问题
Yeah. Water pump.
这辆破车花了200美金
200 bucks for this heap.
它们会让你烦躁不安
Well,they'll get you.
希望我没有多管闲事
Look,I-I hope I'm not out of line,
不过刚才我在那里听到你和警察 说起有关你手的事情
but I heard you telling the cop back there about your hand.
当我还是个孩子的时候 我老父就在越南遇害了
My old man was killed in 'Nam when I was a kid,
所以我对军人非常尊敬
and so I have the utmost respect for our servicemen.
仅仅是为国效劳罢了
Just serving my country.
我们许多人都为此表示感激
A lot of us are grateful for it.
如果你需要搭个顺风车什么的...
Listen,if you need a ride or something...
坦白和你说 我的...
Well,to be honest with you,my...
我的脚走的好酸
my dogs are kind of barking.
好的 上车吧
Well,all right.
我是杰瑞 柯顿
Jerry Curtin.
克莱德  克莱德 梅
Clyde. Clyde May.
我女儿丹尼儿坐在前座
My kid Danny's riding shotgun.
我想你不介意
I hope you don't mind
坐在后面
sittingin the back.
嗨 我是丹尼儿
Hi. I'm Danielle.
嗨 你好
Hi,yourself.
-嘿 -你想干吗?
Hey.What do you want?
我要上洗手间
I need to use the bathroom.
又要去?
Again?
我膀胱小
I have a small bladder.
你们不会都这样吧
That ain't all you got.
起来
Get up.
怎么样?
Well?
他们计划设陷抓你
They plan to trap you.
那个大个子  他在犹他有些朋友
The big one-- he's got friends in Utah.
都是罪犯
Criminals.
一个叫潘圭里奇的小镇
A town called Panguitch.
他们在那里的农场种大麻
They grow drugs on the farm there.
还会告诉你钱在那里 但实际上没有
They'll tell you that's where the money is,but no money.
只有拿着枪的老朋友 在那恭候你大驾
Just old friends with guns,waiting for you.
那很简单
Easy enough.
我们借道潘圭里奇
We take a pass on Panguitch.
钱到底在哪?
Where's the money really?
我会尽快找出来
I'll find out soon enough.
不过现在20万美金是旧行情了
But $200,000 was old price for this information.
我要个新价钱
I want a new price.
你又在和我讨价还价
She's trying to renegotiate.
如果不是我
If it wasn't for me,
你就会倒毙在大麻地里
you'd be face down in a marijuana farm.
三分之一
One third.
那消息可不值这个价
Ha!It's gonna take a lot more than information
如果你想分到三分之一 小宝贝
if you want a million-six,sweet pea.
要做什么?
Such as?
你知道的
You know.
我一直都想要的那个
Piece of that can anytime I want it.
就是那个?
Is that it?
你不打算打我一巴掌吗?
Aren't you gonna slap me?
我和很多男人都睡过觉  相信我
I've slept with men for a lot less,trust me.
那么你说过的"想都别想"如何解释呢?
And what happened to "never in a 1,000 years?"
那是谈判
That was negotiating.
那么
So.
成交了?
Deal?
成交
Deal.
我找到15万美金的现金 约翰
We got a $150,000 here,John.
就在维托利奥在索拉纳斯的住处找到的
With Vittorio's place in Solanas,
我们靠这些利息都能过活了
we'll be able to live off the interest.
你们的父亲呢?
Where's your father?
都好了吗 老大?
Everything all right,boss?
是的
Yeah.
让我们把这档事了结了...
Let's get this over with...
这样我就能回到家人身边了
so I can get back to my family.
她能搞定的
She'll get it done.
妮卡和我共同经历了很多
Nika and I have come too far together.
当钱就在眼前 你就不能相信任何人
When money's on the line,you trust no one.
有时候你必须相信
Sometimes you have to.
如果你想活命 你就不能
Not if you want to survive,you don't.
你真的谁也不相信 是吗?
You really don't trust anyone,do you?
在发生那么多事后 你还来责问我?
Can you blame me after all that's happened?
不 我是说在那之前
No,I mean before that.
进监狱之前
Before prison.
每当我相信某人  我都会受伤
Every time I trusted someone,I got burned.
每当我接近某人 我就会受到不公的对待
Every time I got close to someone,I got screwed.
这点我很清楚 你也应该是
I know better,and so should you.
没错 就是莲花旅馆
That's right,the Lotus Motel.
我不知道电话号码
I don't know the number.
我不能再说下去了 我得挂了
I can't talk anymore; I have to go.
噢 听着
Oh,check it.
我知道这可能有点冒昧
I-I know this might be a little forward and all,
不过 让我
but,um,let me
问你点事
ask you something.
你有男人吗?
You got a man?
我是指男朋友?
I mean,a boyfriend?
不 我在想什么? 你是摩门教徒...
No. What am I thinking? You're Mormon...
我不是
I'm not Mormon.
你以为所有的犹他女孩都是摩门教徒吗?
You think all girls from Utah are Mormons?
是啊 难道不是?
They are,aren't they?
嘿
Well,yo,hey.
哟 那你能参加晚会 是吗?
Yo,then you can party,right?
嘿
Hey.
当我到达的时候 我要12名武装好的特工
When I land,I want 12 armed agents
在那儿待命
waiting for me on the ground.
告诉他们我要直接飞去旅馆
Tell them I want to go straight to the motel from the airstrip.
听明白了吗
You got it.
我以前是个白痴 我道歉
I was an ass before. I apologize.
有一点
A little bit.
好了
It's all right.
给你
Here you go. Thanks.
我还是个超级大白痴
I was a huge ass.
我道歉
I apologize.
我不和你争
I'm not going to argue with you.
我是说
Well,I  mean,
你居然是个医生让我大吃一惊
what were the odds that you were actually a doctor?
噢 可以了 够了
Uh,all right,fair enough.
那可能不大好 但是 呃...
They're probably not good,but,um...
我不该
And I should not
打断你 我很抱歉
have interrupted you,and I'm sorry.
我也很抱歉
I'm sorry,too.
好吧 那么 接受道歉
Well,then,apologies accepted.
向你推荐蓝莓派
I,uh,recommend the blueberry pie.
好 蓝莓派不错
Well,blueberry pie it is.
嘿 丹尼儿
Hey,there,Danny.
嘿 你在这啊
Hey.```````````
你爸爸人真好
Sure is nice of your daddy
还给我今晚订了个房间
to buy me a room for the night.
是的 他总是帮助老兵和一些需要帮助的人
Yeah,he's always helping out with vets and stuff.
是啊 一个好人
Yeah,good man.
好人
Good man.
我真希望
But I was wishing
我们可以一起去犹他州
we could have kept going on toward Utah.
白天阳光明媚 可以四处走走
Lots of light left in the day,lots of road to go.
爸爸停下来的时候  我们就不走了
When Dad's back acts up,we stop.
少女时代?
Young Miss?
看那个不是有些侮辱你吗?
That's kind of insulting,isn't it?
嗯?
Hmm?
我是说你已是个成熟的女人了
I mean,you're a grown woman.
不过大人们总是把
But adults are always trying to infantilize girls your age,
你这个年纪的姑娘当作孩子来看待
treat you like children.
别说笑了
No duh.
我爸爸不让我戴耳环 而且我只有14岁
My dad won't let me get earrings,and I'm 14.
你看?  那就是我要说的
You see? That's what I'm saying.
你更有能力完全...
You are more than perfectly capable of,uh...
自己做决定...
of making your own decisions...
和我爸爸去说吧
Tell my dad that.
是啊 不过他听不进去 是吧?
Yeah,but he won't want to hear it,right?
因为他想让你一直是个小孩子
Because he wants to keep you as a baby.
对吗? 即便
Right? Even though
你 你已经足够大
you're-you're... you're more than old enough
来选择
to-to choose
你想怎么穿衣服 或者
how you want to-to dress,or,
怎么打扮
uh,accessorize.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
- 只是朋友间的需要 就这些... - 不 不 我要告诉爸爸去
Just in need of a friend,that's all... No. No. I'm telling my dad.
站住
Wait!
她完全搞错了
She's got it all wrong.
在外面等着
Go wait outside.
我们得把这事解决下
You and I are gonna work this out.
杰瑞... 你不能这么做
Jerry... you really don't want to do this.
我欣赏你的直接
Thing I like about you is your determination.
我在克拉德诺的家人还在等我
I've got family in Kladno that have been waiting for me
给他们寄钱去
to send for them.
他们知道你现在在做什么吗?
They know what kind of work you're in?
他们以为我在星巴克工作
They think I work at Starbuck's.
你以为我有多蠢?
How stupid do you think I am?
我爸爸总是说 "你耍我一次 我羞辱还你
My daddy always said,"Fool me once,shame on you.
再耍我一次 就把你打翻在地"
Fool me twice,and I put you in the ground."
再耍花样
Any more games,
我就拧断这婊子的脖子 明白吗?
and I stop the hooker's air,understand?
谢谢你的舞蹈 小宝贝
Thanks for the dance,sweet pea.
他妈的
You bitch!
耍的就是你
Fooled you.
我把胎拿来了 他们可以去换胎了
I carried it; the cons can change it.
噢 你太烂了 贝利克
Oh,you really suck,Bellick,
你意识到了吗?
you know that?
绑起来
Roll 'em.
我们走
Let's go.
把手放后面
Put your hands behind your back.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道你和那个医生一样蠢吗?
You're as stupid as the prison doc,you know that?
别理他
Ignore him.
他也玩弄了她 让她误以为他爱上了自己
He conned her,too. Made her think he loved her,
看看她都得到了些什么
and look what she got.
过量注射吗啡 面临30年牢狱之灾
An overdose and a shot at 30 years inside.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我想你还没有看过报纸吧
Guess you haven't been reading the papers,
看过吗 大学生?
have you,college boy?
警方发现你女朋友的时候
Cops found your girlfriend--
已经眼睛翻白 口吐白沫
fish-belly white,garglin' her own puke.
闭嘴
Shut up.
但是你又关心过她吗?
But what do you care,
自从她给你留了门后
a long as she leftthe door open for you?
闭嘴!
Shut up!
说到你痛处了吧?
Hit a sore spot,didn't I?
爸爸...
Dad...
这是我吃过的最好的派了
It really is like the best pie I've ever had.
你知道怎么才能做个派吗?
You know what it needs though... Hmm?
一些脆皮饼  （注：还可解释为强效可卡因，一语双关）
Some crack.
不 我的意思是说不用很多
No,I mean,you know,not a lot.
一小撮
A pinch.
一小撮脆皮饼?  一小撮脆皮饼
A pinch of crack? A pinch of crack.
一小撮脆皮饼 一小口咂咂
A pinch of crack,a dollop of smack.
美味
Mm.
那就做成了一个好吃的派
That's good pie.
那可大错特错了
That's so wrong.
不是吗?
No?
抱歉 接个电话
I'm sorry.
喂
Hello.
莎拉...是我
Sara... it's me.
你要怎样?
What do you want?
我没有时间和你说
I don't have time to talk.
而且很可能
And there's every chance
他们正监听着这通电话
they're listening to this call right now,
但是我还是有很多话想对你说
but there's a lot I want to say.
请不要挂电话
Please don't hang up on me.
我不想...我不想和你说下去了
I don't... I don't want to talk to you.
我听说了...
I heard about...
我听说你都发生了些什么
I heard about what happened.
我想让你知道...
I want you to know that...
我想让你知道我对你的愧疚有多深
I want you to know how sorry I am...
对所发生的一切
for everything.
一声抱歉对我所处的现状根本于事无补
Sorry's not going to do me a whole lot of good with what I'm up against right now.
听着...
Listen...
任何与我及我哥哥关联的人
anyone with any ties to me and my brother
现在都处于危险之中
is in danger now.
我和你及你哥哥再无任何瓜葛
I have no ties to you and your brother anymore.
我有个法子可以保护你
There is a way I can protect you.
已经在你那里了
It's already in your possession.
你都在说些什么?
W-What are you talking about?
是真的 莎拉
It was real,Sara.
你和我...
You and me...
是真的
it's real.
迈克尔?
Michael?
我...
I...
迈克尔?
Michael?
到汽车旅馆还要多久?
How long to the motel?
大约十分钟
Approximately ten minutes,sir.
给你五分钟搞定
Let's make it five?
我还没有这么舒服地洗过澡
Yo,I haven't taken a shower like that
从来没有过!
in forever!
你要去哪?
Where are you going?
我要给你个惊喜
I was going to surprise you.
怎么个惊喜法?
Surprise me how?
我去买点龙舌兰酒还有柠檬
I was going to get some tequila and limes.
-好的 等我一下 -不 不用了
All right,well,hold up-- No,no.
不用 只需要一会儿
No,it'll only take a minute.
呆在这儿 放轻松就行
Stay here and relax.
你看上去有些紧张
You seem kind of nervous.
有吗?
I do?
是的 你都出汗了
Yeah,you're sweating.
或许我是有些紧张
Maybe I am nervous.
相信我  你什么都不用担心 好吗?
Trust me,girl,you got nothing to worry about,all right?
我是个好人
I'm one of the good guys.
看起来是个好人
You seem like it.
别熄火
Hang on tight.
-我让经理把门打开了 -好的
I had the manager unlock the door. Gotcha.
如果你是在找菲波纳奇的话 约翰
If you're looking for the rat,John...
他就在离这2000英里的地方
Fibonacci's 2,000 miles from here.
你是谁?
Who are you?
当地警局的还是联邦调查局的?
Local cops or Feds?
联邦调查局的 约翰
Feds,John,
对付你这种大佬只能派最精干的警察
only roll out the best for a man of your stature.
我要知道是谁出卖了我
I deserve to know who turned on me.
告诉我
Tell me.
这个男人现在进退两难
The man was facing a RICO rap.
他不想进监狱
He did not want to go to prison.
了解你现在的处境
I'm sure you can appreciate that,
我想你会很感激的
knowing what you know about the place now.
无论你现在想做什么 约翰...都别做
Whatever you're thinking about doing,John... don't.
你今天就得回到福克斯河  或者是太平间...
You are going back to Fox River today,or the morgue...
决定权在你
that's your call.
出来吧
Coming out.
先把武器丢出来 约翰
Weapons comes out first,John.
宽恕我吧
Forgive me.
好 我这就出来
Yeah,I'm coming out.
放松 约翰
Easy,John.
放松
Easy.
他有武器 右手
We got a weapon,right hand.
这些人可都不是好惹的
These are serious men here.
你一有行动他们就会向你开枪
They have instructions to shoot at the first sign of aggression.
拜托
Please.
我在和你谈 很恭敬地
I'm asking you,respectfully,
放下武器
drop the weapon,
跪下 把手放在脑后
kneel and put your hands on your head.
我只向上帝下跪
I kneel only to God.
我没看见他在这
I don't see Him here.
约翰!
John!
我想我把事搞砸了
I think I screwed up.
我父亲是空军上校
My dad's an Air Force colonel.
控制欲极强
Total Nazi.
他就是那种
One of those...
令人窒息的严密控管型父亲
nightmare overprotective dads. Mmm-hmm.
然后呢?
Yeah?
我给他打了电话
Well,I called him.
我告诉他我和你一起在旅途中
Told him I was traveling with you.
我还告诉他我们睡在一个房间里
I told him that we were staying in the same hotel room.
-傻丫头  -什么?
Girl. What?
你该学学如何撒谎
You got to learn how to lie,girl.
你觉得呢?
What you thinking? I don't...
没错  出于某种原因 我还真不会撒谎
Yeah,I-- for some reason I don't know how.
当我告诉他我和一个男人在宾馆开房
He-he was mad enough when I told him I was staying
他抓狂不已
in a hotel room with a guy,
-这是一回事...  -然后呢
that was one thing... Yeah,yeah.
但是当我告诉他
but when I told him I was staying in a hotel
我和一男人在宾馆开房时
with a guy that...
我或许就像那种...
I maybe sort of liked...
他再也管不了我了
he lost it.
等等
Wait.
等什么?
Wait,what?
你没事吧?
Is that okay?
至少让我们把你送到镇上吧
At least let us take you into town.
不用了
No.
如果我被发现和你在一起
If I'm seen with you,
那就麻烦大了
it's a lot of trouble for me.
我能步行过去 只有一里路而已
I can walk; it's only a mile.
没有你的帮助 我们到不了现在这步
We never would've made it this far without you.
但是你会丢下我
But now you're crossing the border...
穿过边境...
without me.
你不能和我们一起去那儿
You can't go where we're going.
因为那不是你的人生
It's not a life for you.
如果说那就是我的人生呢
Then that's it then.
好吧  一切都结束了
It's over for good.
谢谢
Thank you.
注意安全
Be safe.
好运
Good luck.
我爱过你 迈克尔
I loved you,Michael.
我想我应该放弃这段感情
And I thought I was going to get that back,
你仅仅是利用我而已
but you just used me.
不是那样的
That's not true.
我应该比这得到的更多
I deserve more than this.
绝对不止仅当个
I deserve more than just being the girl
你需要帮忙 就一个电话过来的女子
that you call when you need something.
你真的认为你能在犹他州找到那笔钱?
You really think you're gonna find the money in Utah?
我根本不在乎埋在犹他州的钱!
I don't care about the money in Utah!
我不想再犯罪了
I don't want any more crime.
我把你们抓起来 我就能得到20万
I turn you in,I get $200,000.
合法的钱
Legal money.
现在就把你们交给警方
You're the policemen's problem now.
-妮卡... -别再靠过来 不然我就开枪了!
Nika... Don't come any closer or I'll shoot you!
不 你开不了枪
No,you won't.
祝你好运
Good luck to you.
呃 总部来电
Um,HQ called.
询问你为什么不在阿布鲁奇
They're asking why you didn't intercept Abruzzi
走向汽车旅馆的时候就中途截住他
when he was walking towards the motel.
这家伙是黑帮老大
The man was a mob boss.
正确的行动就是困住他
The right move was to get him trapped.
他们说你这么做
They're saying the way you played it,
结果只有一个
there was only one possible outcome.
总部对我的行动有异议的话
HQ has a problem with the way I do things,
那下次让他们也拿起枪
they can pick up a gun
跟着我到现场处理
and follow me into the field next time.
斯科菲尔德一直知道菲波纳奇是吊住阿布鲁奇的关键
Scofield always knew the rat was the key to Abruzzi.
我们偏偏把这个诱饵公布出来 这样阿布鲁奇就会上钩了
We just put it out on the wire and Abruzzi bit.
说到斯科菲尔德...
Speaking of Scofield...
撞车是设计好的障眼法
That crash was staged.
是猪血
Pig blood.
真狡猾啊
Smart kid.
问题是...
The problem with...
太过狡猾迟早会
being that clever is that sooner or later,
聪明反被聪明误
you end up getting too clever for your own good.
晚安
Good night.
你自己都不清楚会面对什么
You've no idea what you're in for.